(#) Notes:
->HTML - displays the content on webpage.
->CSS - Styles the webpage.
->JavaScript - Validates & takes action.
(1) Client Side gives valid & invalid Data.
(2) Server Side validates & take necessary action.
(3) If the valid data is entered server side ask to database for required data.
(4) If the invalid data is entered, sever side takes necessary action.

(#) Without JavaScript all the validation take place in server side which increase the load of the server, because of which the site may be crashed. JavaScript is a frontend technology, used to validate the data, also helps to reduce the server's load. Because of JavaScript all the validation and action take place in client side only.

(#) JavaScript:
(1) We are sending only valid data to server side.
(2) Using javaSvrip the load of server will get reduce.
(3) Validation and action we are performing at client side only.

(#) Linking:
->Internal javascript is used <script> </script> inside <head> </head>
->External JavaScript file is saved using ".js" extension.
To link external js file, the following syntax will be helpful:
<head> <script src = "Demo.js"> </script> </head>

(#) Linking
->External Cascading Style Sheet is saved using ".css" extension.
->To link external css file, the following syntax will be helpful:
<head> <link href = "style.css" rel = "stylesheet"> </head>

(#) In JavaScript webpage is known as document.

(#) To comment:
 // for single line comment
 /* for multiline comment */

(#) Variables and datatypes in JavaScript
 JavaScript is dynamically typed programming language.
 In JavaScript datatypes will get assign to the variables during runtime by language interpreter.
 (1) number: To store the real and integer numbers.
 (2) string: To store the character or strings.
 (3) boolean: To store true or false.
 (4) object: To refer the objects.
 (5) undefined: datatypes to those varibles which is not initialise but defined using var or let keyword
 (6) array:

(#) Keywords: var, let, const
->In js, datatypes are not required to decalre variables, but we have to use keywords (var, let, const) as per requirements, which describe the scope of variables.
->var keyword: Whenever we declare any variable using keyword "var", then that variable does not have scope only inside the block. Redeclaring any variable using var keyword inside same block is allowed. 
->let keyword: We can't redeclare varible using "let" keyword in a same block i.e., if it is declared globally then another time it can't be redeclared anywhere globally but it can be redeclared once inside the different blocks.
Variables declared using let can't be accessible outside the block's scope.
->const keyword: We can't redeclare varible using "const" keyword in same block i.e., if it id declared globally then another time it can't be redecalred anywhere globally but it can be redeclared once inside the different blocks. 
->Redefinition is not allowed for the variables that is declared "const". Const keyword makes it constant.
->Variable declared using const can't be accessible outside the block's scope.
->Non defined varible can't be declared using const keyword.
console.log() is used to see the error in the console tab present inside inspection option of the browser.

->typeof() is used to check the datatype of varibale.
->semicolon (;) is option in javascript.

(#) TypeCasting: is a mechanism, which is used to convert one datatype into another type.
 Number(), String(), Boolean(), Array() and Object() are the methods which are used in typecasting.
 (1) Number can be casted into Number, String, Boolean and Object but not to undefined and Array.
 (2) String can be casted into Number, String, Boolean, Object, Array but not to undefined. If String contains real or integer value only not other character then it works perfectly otherwise it stores NaN.
 (3) Boolean can be casted into Number, String, Boolean, Object, Array but not to undefined.
 (4) Array can be casted into Number, String, Boolean, Object and Array but not to undefined. If array contains only single element as real or integer then it works perfectly at the time of typecasting from array to number otherwise it stores NaN.
 (5) Undefined can be casted into Number, String, Boolean, Object and Array also.

(#) Array in JavaScript:
 Array in JS can store homogeneous & heterogenous type of data. We can access data from array using index. 
->Declaration of Array
  var n = [];
  var n = new Array();
->Declare and Define Array
  var n = [1, "Akhilesh", true];
  var n = new Array(1, "Akhilesh", true);
->Fetching data from array
  document.write(n); Display all the elements
  console.log(n); Same functionality
  console.log(n[2]); fetch the element present at second index
->Add element into array
  n[index] = element;
  n.push(element); at last index and return the new length of array
  n.unshift(element); append at the 0th index of an array
->Delete element from array
  n.pop(); removes the last element from an array
  n.shift(); removes elements from the 0th index of an array
->splice() is used to delete also to add element
  splice(start_index, no_of_element); deletes no of elements from specified position
  splice(start-index, no_of_element, elements_seperating_using_comma); it first deletes no fo elements from specified position then from the specified position it will start to add the element and if the element already present at last of array then it will shift them to new indexes.
  splice() return the elements which has been deleted from the array.

(#) Operators
1. Arithmatic Operator: + - * /
2. Relation Operator: < > == <= >= !=
3. Logical Operator: && ||
4. Ternary Operator: (conditon) ? Exp1 : Exp2;
5. String Operator: +